<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily Newsletter</title><link>http://davidshadle.com</link><description>Daily curated headlines from around the world.</description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 20:58:32 </lastBuildDate><item><title>U.S. and Israel Strike Iranian Nuclear Sites</title><description>The U.S. and Israel launched coordinated attacks on Iran’s Fordow nuclear facility, using bunker-buster bombs and cruise missiles. The UN warns of a “spiral of chaos” as Iran vows retaliation.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26</pubDate><guid>U.S. and Israel Strike Iranian Nuclear Sites</guid></item><item><title>Iran Vows Response as Israel Hits Tehran</title><description>Israel expanded its strikes to include six Iranian airports and parts of Tehran, including Evin Prison. Iran’s foreign minister condemned the attacks as sabotage of ongoing diplomacy.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26</pubDate><guid>Iran Vows Response as Israel Hits Tehran</guid></item><item><title>UN Chief Condemns Escalation in Middle East</title><description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres called the U.S. bombing of Iranian nuclear sites a “perilous turn” and urged all parties to de-escalate immediately.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26</pubDate><guid>UN Chief Condemns Escalation in Middle East</guid></item><item><title>Russia Launches Deadly Airstrikes on Kyiv</title><description>A major Russian drone and missile attack killed at least 10 people in Kyiv, striking residential areas and a hospital. It’s the second such attack in a week.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26</pubDate><guid>Russia Launches Deadly Airstrikes on Kyiv</guid></item><item><title>Global Airlines Suspend Flights Over Middle East</title><description>Major airlines have halted or rerouted flights due to escalating conflict between Israel and Iran. The aviation industry is bracing for prolonged disruption.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26</pubDate><guid>Global Airlines Suspend Flights Over Middle East</guid></item><item><title>Iranian Foreign Minister Meets Putin in Moscow</title><description>Iran’s Abbas Araghchi met with Russian President Vladimir Putin to discuss the crisis. Russia has called for restraint and warned against further escalation.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26</pubDate><guid>Iranian Foreign Minister Meets Putin in Moscow</guid></item><item><title>Trump Defends Strikes, Hints at Regime Change</title><description>President Trump defended the strikes as a “spectacular success” and hinted at regime change in Iran, despite intelligence assessments that Iran was not building nuclear weapons.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26</pubDate><guid>Trump Defends Strikes, Hints at Regime Change</guid></item><item><title>U.S. Congress Divided Over Iran Strikes</title><description>Trump ordered the strikes without congressional approval, briefing only Republican lawmakers. Democrats have condemned the move as unconstitutional.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26</pubDate><guid>U.S. Congress Divided Over Iran Strikes</guid></item><item><title>Oil Prices Surge, Then Stabilize</title><description>Oil prices spiked following the strikes but stabilized after OPEC+ reassured markets of supply continuity. Analysts warn of volatility if the Strait of Hormuz is threatened.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26</pubDate><guid>Oil Prices Surge, Then Stabilize</guid></item><item><title>UN Security Council Holds Emergency Session</title><description>The UN Security Council convened an emergency meeting to address the Middle East crisis. Several nations called for immediate ceasefire and diplomatic talks.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26</pubDate><guid>UN Security Council Holds Emergency Session</guid></item><item><title>EU Ministers Meet Amid Iran Crisis</title><description>European foreign ministers gathered in Brussels to discuss the Iran-Israel conflict. The bloc is divided on whether to impose sanctions or push for diplomacy.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26</pubDate><guid>EU Ministers Meet Amid Iran Crisis</guid><category>European Union</category></item><item><title>France Heightens Security After Iran Strikes</title><description>France has increased security at embassies and key infrastructure. President Macron called for a unified EU response.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26</pubDate><guid>France Heightens Security After Iran Strikes</guid><category>France</category></item><item><title>Germany Accelerates Renewable Energy Push</title><description>Germany announced a fast-track plan to expand wind and solar energy in response to energy instability. The move is part of a broader EU strategy to reduce reliance on Middle Eastern oil.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26</pubDate><guid>Germany Accelerates Renewable Energy Push</guid><category>Germany</category></item><item><title>UK Scientists Join Global Climate Monitoring Network</title><description>British researchers are contributing to a new international initiative to track climate change using satellite and oceanic data.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26</pubDate><guid>UK Scientists Join Global Climate Monitoring Network</guid><category>United Kingdom</category></item><item><title>Scandinavia Launches Joint AI Ethics Framework</title><description>Norway, Sweden, and Denmark introduced a shared framework for ethical AI development, emphasizing transparency and human oversight.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26</pubDate><guid>Scandinavia Launches Joint AI Ethics Framework</guid><category>Scandinavia</category></item><item><title>Vera Rubin Observatory in Jeopardy Before Launch</title><description>Funding and logistical issues threaten the launch of the Vera Rubin Observatory, a major astronomical project expected to revolutionize dark matter research.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26</pubDate><guid>Vera Rubin Observatory in Jeopardy Before Launch</guid></item><item><title>Record-Breaking Black Hole Discovered</title><description>Scientists have identified a black hole with unprecedented mass and spin, challenging current astrophysical models.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26</pubDate><guid>Record-Breaking Black Hole Discovered</guid></item><item><title>First Images of the Sun’s South Pole Released</title><description>A European solar mission captured the first high-resolution images of the Sun’s south pole, offering new insights into solar wind and magnetic fields.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26</pubDate><guid>First Images of the Sun’s South Pole Released</guid></item><item><title>AI Reveals Milky Way’s Black Hole Faces Earth</title><description>A new AI model suggests the supermassive black hole at the center of our galaxy is oriented toward Earth. Scientists say there’s no danger, but it’s a significant discovery.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26</pubDate><guid>AI Reveals Milky Way’s Black Hole Faces Earth</guid></item><item><title>Lost World Discovered Beneath Antarctica</title><description>Geologists uncovered a submerged ancient landscape beneath Antarctica’s ice, possibly containing fossilized ecosystems.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26</pubDate><guid>Lost World Discovered Beneath Antarctica</guid></item></channel></rss>