<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Daily Newsletter</title><link>http://davidshadle.com</link><description>Daily curated headlines from around the world.</description><language>en-us</language><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 20:34:14 </pubDate><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 20:34:14 </lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://davidshadle.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>U.S. and Israel Launch Strikes on Iranian Nuclear Sites</title><description>The U.S. and Israel have conducted coordinated airstrikes on Iran’s Fordow nuclear facility and other military targets, escalating tensions in the Middle East. The UN warns of a “spiral of chaos” as Iran vows retaliation.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26 +0000</pubDate><link>http://davidshadle.com/global1</link><guid>http://davidshadle.com/global1</guid><category>Global</category></item><item><title>Global Markets Show Resilience Amid Middle East Crisis</title><description>Despite the geopolitical shock, global markets remained stable, with oil prices briefly spiking before settling. Analysts attribute the calm to OPEC+ spare capacity and investor confidence in containment.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26 +0000</pubDate><link>http://davidshadle.com/global2</link><guid>http://davidshadle.com/global2</guid><category>Global</category></item><item><title>South Korea Declares Emergency Over Middle East Tensions</title><description>President Lee Jae-myung activated emergency measures to protect South Korea’s economy, heavily reliant on Middle Eastern oil. The government is preparing supplemental budgets and fuel reserves.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26 +0000</pubDate><link>http://davidshadle.com/global3</link><guid>http://davidshadle.com/global3</guid><category>Global</category></item><item><title>Russian Airstrikes Kill 10 in Kyiv</title><description>A major Russian drone and missile attack on Kyiv has killed at least 10 people, striking residential areas and a hospital. This marks the second such attack in a week.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26 +0000</pubDate><link>http://davidshadle.com/global4</link><guid>http://davidshadle.com/global4</guid><category>Global</category></item><item><title>Zelenskiy Visits UK to Request More Defense Aid</title><description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy is in the UK seeking additional military support. NATO is expected to raise defense spending targets at its upcoming summit.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26 +0000</pubDate><link>http://davidshadle.com/global5</link><guid>http://davidshadle.com/global5</guid><category>Global</category></item><item><title>Thailand Reshuffles Cabinet Amid Political Tensions</title><description>Thailand’s government announced a Cabinet reshuffle to stabilize its coalition after the Bhumjaithai party’s exit. The move aims to restore confidence and legislative momentum.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26 +0000</pubDate><link>http://davidshadle.com/global6</link><guid>http://davidshadle.com/global6</guid><category>Global</category></item><item><title>UN Chief Condemns Escalation in Middle East</title><description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres expressed grave concern over the U.S. and Israeli strikes, calling for immediate de-escalation. He warned the region cannot endure another cycle of destruction.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26 +0000</pubDate><link>http://davidshadle.com/global7</link><guid>http://davidshadle.com/global7</guid><category>Global</category></item><item><title>Iran Threatens to Close Strait of Hormuz</title><description>In response to the attacks, Iran has hinted at closing the Strait of Hormuz, a critical global oil shipping route. Such a move could have major implications for global energy markets.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26 +0000</pubDate><link>http://davidshadle.com/global8</link><guid>http://davidshadle.com/global8</guid><category>Global</category></item><item><title>U.S. Political Divide Over Iran Strikes</title><description>President Trump ordered the strikes without congressional approval, briefing only select Republican lawmakers. Democrats and international observers have criticized the move as reckless.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26 +0000</pubDate><link>http://davidshadle.com/global9</link><guid>http://davidshadle.com/global9</guid><category>Global</category></item><item><title>Global Diplomatic Push to Prevent Wider War</title><description>World leaders, including Russia’s Putin and EU officials, are urging restraint and renewed diplomacy. Emergency UN Security Council meetings are underway.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26 +0000</pubDate><link>http://davidshadle.com/global10</link><guid>http://davidshadle.com/global10</guid><category>Global</category></item><item><title>EU Ministers Meet Amid Iran Crisis</title><description>European Union foreign ministers convened in Brussels to discuss the escalating conflict between the U.S., Israel, and Iran. The bloc is divided on how to respond, with some members calling for sanctions and others urging diplomacy.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26 +0000</pubDate><link>http://davidshadle.com/europe1</link><guid>http://davidshadle.com/europe1</guid><category>Europe</category></item><item><title>France Reacts to Iran-Israel Conflict with Heightened Security</title><description>France has increased security at key sites and embassies following the Israeli strikes on Iran. President Macron called for restraint and emphasized the need for a unified EU response.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26 +0000</pubDate><link>http://davidshadle.com/europe2</link><guid>http://davidshadle.com/europe2</guid><category>Europe</category></item><item><title>Germany Pushes for Renewable Energy Acceleration</title><description>In response to energy instability, Germany announced a fast-track plan to expand wind and solar infrastructure. The move is part of a broader EU effort to reduce dependence on Middle Eastern oil.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26 +0000</pubDate><link>http://davidshadle.com/europe3</link><guid>http://davidshadle.com/europe3</guid><category>Europe</category></item><item><title>UK Scientists Join Global Climate Monitoring Network</title><description>British researchers have joined an international initiative to monitor climate change using satellite and oceanic data. The UK’s contribution focuses on Arctic ice melt and sea level rise.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26 +0000</pubDate><link>http://davidshadle.com/europe4</link><guid>http://davidshadle.com/europe4</guid><category>Europe</category></item><item><title>Scandinavian Countries Launch Joint AI Ethics Framework</title><description>Norway, Sweden, and Denmark have introduced a shared framework for ethical AI development. The initiative emphasizes transparency, data privacy, and human oversight.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26 +0000</pubDate><link>http://davidshadle.com/europe5</link><guid>http://davidshadle.com/europe5</guid><category>Europe</category></item><item><title>Vera Rubin Observatory in Jeopardy Before Inauguration</title><description>Funding and logistical challenges threaten the launch of the Vera Rubin Observatory, a major astronomical project expected to revolutionize our understanding of dark matter. Scientists warn delays could set back key cosmic surveys by years.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26 +0000</pubDate><link>http://davidshadle.com/science1</link><guid>http://davidshadle.com/science1</guid><category>Science &amp; Discovery</category></item><item><title>Black Hole Discovery Breaks All Records</title><description>Astronomers have identified a black hole with mass and spin characteristics never before observed, challenging current models of stellar evolution. The discovery was made using data from the Event Horizon Telescope.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26 +0000</pubDate><link>http://davidshadle.com/science2</link><guid>http://davidshadle.com/science2</guid><category>Science &amp; Discovery</category></item><item><title>First Images of the Sun’s South Pole Released</title><description>A European solar mission has captured the first high-resolution images of the Sun’s south pole, offering new insights into solar wind and magnetic field dynamics. This could improve space weather forecasting.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26 +0000</pubDate><link>http://davidshadle.com/science3</link><guid>http://davidshadle.com/science3</guid><category>Science &amp; Discovery</category></item><item><title>AI Reveals Milky Way’s Black Hole Is Pointing Toward Earth</title><description>A new AI model analyzing galactic data suggests the supermassive black hole at the center of the Milky Way is oriented toward Earth. Scientists emphasize there’s no danger, but the alignment is scientifically significant.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26 +0000</pubDate><link>http://davidshadle.com/science4</link><guid>http://davidshadle.com/science4</guid><category>Science &amp; Discovery</category></item><item><title>Lost World Discovered Beneath Antarctica</title><description>Geologists have uncovered evidence of a submerged ancient landscape beneath Antarctica’s ice, possibly containing fossilized ecosystems. The discovery could reshape theories about Earth’s prehistoric climate.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26 +0000</pubDate><link>http://davidshadle.com/science5</link><guid>http://davidshadle.com/science5</guid><category>Science &amp; Discovery</category></item></channel></rss>