<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
    <title>Daily Newsletter</title>
    <link>http://davidshadle.com</link>
    <description>Daily newsletter with global and regional headlines</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26 </pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 19:45:26 </lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Python RSS Generator</generator>

    <item>
        <title>U.S. and Israel Launch Strikes on Iranian Nuclear Sites</title>
        <description>The U.S. and Israel have conducted coordinated airstrikes on Iran’s Fordow nuclear facility and other military targets, escalating tensions in the Middle East. The UN warns of a 'spiral of chaos' as Iran vows retaliation.</description>
        <pubDate>2025-06-23</pubDate>
        <link>http://davidshadle.com</link>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Global Markets Show Resilience Amid Middle East Crisis</title>
        <description>Despite the geopolitical shock, global markets remained stable, with oil prices briefly spiking before settling. Analysts attribute the calm to OPEC+ spare capacity and investor confidence in containment.</description>
        <pubDate>2025-06-23</pubDate>
        <link>http://davidshadle.com</link>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>South Korea Declares Emergency Over Middle East Tensions</title>
        <description>President Lee Jae-myung activated emergency measures to protect South Korea’s economy, heavily reliant on Middle Eastern oil. The government is preparing supplemental budgets and fuel reserves.</description>
        <pubDate>2025-06-23</pubDate>
        <link>http://davidshadle.com</link>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Russian Airstrikes Kill 10 in Kyiv</title>
        <description>A major Russian drone and missile attack on Kyiv has killed at least 10 people, striking residential areas and a hospital. This marks the second such attack in a week.</description>
        <pubDate>2025-06-23</pubDate>
        <link>http://davidshadle.com</link>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Zelenskiy Visits UK to Request More Defense Aid</title>
        <description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy is in the UK seeking additional military support. NATO is expected to raise defense spending targets at its upcoming summit.</description>
        <pubDate>2025-06-23</pubDate>
        <link>http://davidshadle.com</link>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Thailand Reshuffles Cabinet Amid Political Tensions</title>
        <description>Thailand’s government announced a Cabinet reshuffle to stabilize its coalition after the Bhumjaithai party’s exit. The move aims to restore confidence and legislative momentum.</description>
        <pubDate>2025-06-23</pubDate>
        <link>http://davidshadle.com</link>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>UN Chief Condemns Escalation in Middle East</title>
        <description>UN Secretary-General António Guterres expressed grave concern over the U.S. and Israeli strikes, calling for immediate de-escalation. He warned the region cannot endure another cycle of destruction.</description>
        <pubDate>2025-06-23</pubDate>
        <link>http://davidshadle.com</link>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Iran Threatens to Close Strait of Hormuz</title>
        <description>In response to the attacks, Iran has hinted at closing the Strait of Hormuz, a critical global oil shipping route. Such a move could have major implications for global energy markets.</description>
        <pubDate>2025-06-23</pubDate>
        <link>http://davidshadle.com</link>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>U.S. Political Divide Over Iran Strikes</title>
        <description>President Trump ordered the strikes without congressional approval, briefing only select Republican lawmakers. Democrats and international observers have criticized the move as reckless.</description>
        <pubDate>2025-06-23</pubDate>
        <link>http://davidshadle.com</link>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Global Diplomatic Push to Prevent Wider War</title>
        <description>World leaders, including Russia’s Putin and EU officials, are urging restraint and renewed diplomacy. Emergency UN Security Council meetings are underway.</description>
        <pubDate>2025-06-23</pubDate>
        <link>http://davidshadle.com</link>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>UK Cuts Green Levies to Support Industry</title>
        <description>The UK government announced it will remove green levies from energy bills for key industries like automotive and aerospace. The move aims to boost competitiveness amid high energy costs.</description>
        <pubDate>2025-06-23</pubDate>
        <link>http://davidshadle.com</link>
        <category>United Kingdom</category>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Bride Killed in Wedding Party Shooting in France</title>
        <description>A bride was fatally shot during an attack on a wedding party near Avignon, France. The suspected attacker was also killed in what appears to be a targeted incident.</description>
        <pubDate>2025-06-23</pubDate>
        <link>http://davidshadle.com</link>
        <category>France</category>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>EU Council Debates Mental Health Protections for Youth</title>
        <description>European ministers are calling for stronger protections for children and teens from digital-era mental health risks. Proposals include tighter regulation of e-cigarettes and online content.</description>
        <pubDate>2025-06-23</pubDate>
        <link>http://davidshadle.com</link>
        <category>European Union</category>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>EU Approves €202 Million in Aid for Palestinian Services</title>
        <description>The EU has pledged over €200 million to support essential services in Palestinian territories via UNRWA and the Palestinian Authority. The funding aims to stabilize humanitarian conditions.</description>
        <pubDate>2025-06-23</pubDate>
        <link>http://davidshadle.com</link>
        <category>European Union</category>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Commission Reviews Safety of Menstrual Products</title>
        <description>The European Commission is reviewing transparency and safety standards for menstrual products. This follows concerns about chemical composition and consumer health.</description>
        <pubDate>2025-06-23</pubDate>
        <link>http://davidshadle.com</link>
        <category>European Union</category>
    </item>

</channel>
</rss>
